[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome to the ask abijit Show
episode 219 I hope everybody is doing
great um and I'm going to take questions
today from the
uh live chat the comments the questions
will ask me in the live chat but before
we do that let me see who all is on the
live stream I can see kapalin skull
manushi sha pram
Sharma pad kaarna Zu isong geopolitical
historian Shakti Prasad patnayak naen
Kumar exploring Kunal nagaro aru and
ainash Slayer Vishnu mohanan hello Ethan
dunks partial Sage tikish
Rahul UD
feminist Slayer hello threat Ripper
arish coach Anthony gamer Banda Panda
rakit Mishra Amit Krishna not human Raja
shagun Chopra from akashwani Hello
abishek VI pral bman prna amales Jesus
Jesus bro geopolitical dub Raja parijat
diit myala parendra Felix nadii rudra
rindra Chri pritam Sharma Arian sarot
Sumit nand
Hunter
kve Nishan tiari prabhat Agarwal band
panda Shivam tiari feminist Slayer again
Chetan sahu Jay guman mavin hello VI
Tushar kalburgi
Namaste
amales uh Prince Bagel rudra Rush God Ed
take bites murali Sharma swapo Anand
Anand Slayer Itachi space the part
and a whole lot of other people the
English tutor Priyanka jaala hello
viit Mulin Tano chakrawarti AES digpal
lone Rider hsh tiari sushant pael Karan
ra goami and everybody else so uh so I'm
going to take questions from the live
chat but before we do that I'm going to
take one question that's been asked in
the comments so let's find that
question and let's take this one
question question from the comments and
then I'll take questions from the live
chat because this this is a rather
important and pertinent question so vun
vun goil says you have mentioned that
Trump has kissed the ring what's your
opinion on there are no specific people
in the Deep state but the system itself
designed in such a way that it acts as
the Deep state in the end the president
has the highest power but not all power
right that's the question
so we I'm sure people must be aware of
the statement that President Trump has
made and in case you're not aware let me
put that on the screen uh one second
give me a second I'll put that on the
screen so
uh he's put out a video and this tweet
by this account is is a is essentially
the gist of the video I'm not going to
play the video right now mute that so
what did Trump say this is a brief
statement about four minutes long
roughly so here and Trump has explicitly
mentioned mentioned the term deep State
multiple times in this statement and
he's essentially saying that he's going
after the Deep state so here's the gist
let's read this out together the end of
the deep State Trump's plan to dismantle
the Deep State and return power to the
American people and Trump says here's my
plan to dismantle the Deep State and
reclaim our democracy from Washington
corruption once and for all and
Corruption it is first I will
immediately reissue my 2020 executive
order restoring the president's
Authority to remove Rogue bureaucrats
and I'll wield that power very
aggressively so he's going to go after
Rogue bureaucrats okay second we will
clean out all of the corrupt actors in
our national security and intelligence
apparatus and there are plenty of them
the Departments and agencies that have
been weaponized will be completely overh
hold so that faceless bureaucrats that
term again will never again be able to
Target and persecute various people okay
third we will totally reform fisa courts
fisa means United States foreign
intelligence surveillance courts
and these quotes essentially they they
uh this act is all about surveilling
Americans who could be working for
foreign actors you know uh essentially
spies and traitors so we will totally
reform the fisa courts which are so
corrupt that the judges seemingly do not
care when they are lied to in warrant
applications and so on Fourth to expose
the hoaxes and abuses of power that have
been tearing our country apart we will
establish a Truth and Reconciliation
Commission to declassify and publish all
documents on deep State spying
censorship corrupt ion Etc okay
interesting fifth we will launch a major
Crackdown on government leakers who
collude with the fake news media to
deliberately wave false narratives and
all that so he's going going after fake
news okay and the people who are uh
aiding and abetting fake news sixth we
will make every inspector General's
Office Independent and physically
separated from the Departments they
oversee so they don't become Protectors
of the deep State okay good seventh I
will ask Congress to establish an
independent auditing system to
continually monitor our intelligence
agencies to ensure they're not spying on
our citizens or running disinformation
campaigns against the American people or
that they are not spying on someone's
campaign like they spied on my campaign
okay great eth we will continue the
effort launched by the Trump
Administration to move Paths of the
sprawling Federal bureaucracy again
bureaucracy to new locations outside the
Washington swamp just as I mov the
Bureau of whatever to Colorado as many
as 100,000 government positions can be
moved out and I mean immediately out of
Washington to places filled with
Patriots who love America and they
really do love America okay great ninth
I will work to ban Federal bureaucrats
again from taking jobs at the companies
that deal with and that they regulate
okay that's great so they deal with
these companies and they regulate these
companies and when they want to take
jobs from these companies uh doesn't
work that way and so on finally I will
push for a constitutional I will push a
constitutional amendment to impose term
limits on members of Congress and this
is how I will shatter the Deep State and
restore government that is controlled by
the people and for the people okay so
that's the statement that he's making
okay that he's going to go after the
Deep State and when he talks about the
Deep State he's essentially talking
about the bureaucracy the nameless
faceless unelected permanent bureaucracy
um lot of times he has mentioned the
bureaucracy and the bureaucrats in there
and he's going to impo impose term
limits on members of Congress great I
mean Nancy Pelosi has been in Congress
for God knows how many terms okay so
impose term limits on members of
Congress Etc and reform fisa courts and
all that so
these it's a lot of initiatives is going
to take that's what he says right so
does it not mean that he's going after
the Deep State that's the question it's
a very pertinent question and he has
named The Deep State multiple times in
this statement so then the question is
was I wrong that Trump may have kissed
the ring what do I mean by kissing the
ring ring it means making a deal with
the Deep State such that they will now
allow him to come to power that's what I
had meant right and apparently he's
going after the Deep State now let me
put something else on the screen that
may be kind of interesting okay let's
put something else on the screen and
this is a piece of news from three days
ago us Central Bank boss says Trump
can't fire him this is from the BBC and
this is from three days ago as you can
see this piece of news so the head of
the US Central Bank which is the Federal
Reserve has hit back at speculation that
his his post might be in Jeopardy As
Trump prepares to assume power in
Washington so Federal Reserve chairman
Jerome Powell said that he would not
step down even if Trump asked him to
step down and that it is not permitted
under law for the White House to force
him out
yeah how about that Will trump be able
to do a thing about the Federal Reserve
the Federal Reserve Bank is the American
Central Bank it's a Central Bank of the
United States just like with the RBI in
India so the Federal Reserve is a
privately owned bank it's not owned by
the government and its ownership
structure is kind of hazy and kind of
shrouded in
mystery right uh who are the
shareholders Etc I mean there is some
information available about who could be
the shareholders and all that but the
real shareholders are kind of shrouded
in Myster and the White House under us
law can't make changes in here
interesting there interesting can Trump
do a thing about this the Federal
Reserve Bank controls the entire US
economy and by extension
a significant portion of the global
world world
economy they can well impact everybody
across the world through whatever
changes they make the policy decisions
uh interest rate changes and whatnot so
there's one example of what Trump can't
do he's going to go after the
bureaucracy the nameless faceless
bureaucrat is going to go after fa fisa
courts he going to go he's going to
impose term limits on me members of
Congress is going to ensure that members
of Congress and other elected people
cannot not have conflicts of interest
and serve various corporations and
things like that great great wonderful
so he's going to cut go after the
bureaucracy essentially right now let me
give you a a different but kind of
pertinent example Elon Musk a couple of
years ago or whenever it was he took
over Twitter and he rebranded it to X
and Elon Musk fired 90% of Twitter's
employees didn't he and yet after firing
90% of Twitter's employees Twitter is
better and bigger than ever before so
getting rid of the
bloat is actually good for an
organization so if Trump goes after all
these nameless faceless bureaucrats and
gets rid of a whole bunch of them and
and imposes restrictions on them and and
the way you know in the sense of what
they can do what they can't do and move
a a whole bunch of them 100,000 of them
outside of Washington in various other
parts of the US is he going after the
Deep state so now let's do some first
principles thinking analysis the
question we have to ask ourselves is
what is the Deep State what's the
definition of the deep State and I have
given this definition or answer before
multiple times the Deep state
is an extra Democratic extra
constitutional extra electoral Center of
power in a nation
in the US we're talking about the US
here so it's a center of power a bunch
of really powerful people who are extra
Democratic means they cannot be removed
democratically or whichever way extra
constitutional the Constitution has no
mandate for these people being in having
such positions of power and extra
Democratic extra electoral you can't
vote them out or whatever it's a
completely separate Power Center that's
the Deep state it means it's a small
number of very powerful individuals who
are the Puppet Masters who control these
these institutions these agencies the
bureaucrats and so
on so going after the bureaucrats is
wonderful great job but you're not going
after the ones who are really in power
who really hold the Reigns of power the
past four years Biden was not mentally
present Kamala Harris was incompetent we
all know that and still somebody was
running the United States of America it
was running really efficiently really
well I mean they did mess up the economy
and all but maybe that was on
purpose maybe so is Trump really going
after the the real source of power or is
he doing a lot of all this noise about
going after
low-level easy to Target bureaucrats
maybe that was the deal you say that
you're going after the Deep State and
you go after the bureaucrats and that
way you make the American
government Machinery even more efficient
the way Elon Musk
did what's the dog Department of govern
government efficiency that's a new thing
that they they proposed and Elon Musk
will be part of that maybe he will head
that so they will cut down the bloat and
go after the bureaucrats but that
doesn't change anything up High where
the real power lies so is Trump really
going after the Deep state or is he
actually empowering the Deep State and
making their governance Machinery way
more powerful than it has ever been
before that's the
question and it looks like he's not
going after the people who are really in
power the shadowy figures behind all the
scenes who who wield the real power who
are way more powerful than the president
and the government of the US is not
going after them he dare not go after
them so has he kissed the
ring I I will leave it for you to answer
Pik is the ring okay so okay that's
that's the uh question
and now let's take uh questions from the
live chat okay um let's see let's see
let's see okay this is by honey why is
the United States pushing India into the
other Camp if r i happens then the
combined hard power in the economy would
be nearly of 75 and 25t I'm assuming
trillions or something if I know it here
I'm sure the US must be aware of this
and then
why okay the US is is see what's the US
doing Visa V India uh it's using see now
now you must have heard the news that
the the so-called khalistani fake
movement it's even uh rearing its head
in New Zealand so there are five five
eyes Nations the United States is the
boss and then there's the UK there's
Canada there's Australia and there's New
Zealand and we know that there's
significant khalistani activity in in
Canada there is that in the UK there is
significant such activ Kalani activity
in Australia and now even New Zealand
has been activated so all the five eyes
Nations have been activated Vis this
kalist thing it's a pressure tactic it's
about uh arm twisting the government of
India into being more amable to the
United States and and aligning itself
strongly more more strongly with the
West let's say right now India is first
pursuing an independent for foreign
policy they would like us to tow their
life
and completely cut off relations with
Russia and whatever with China and so
on so that's a pressure tactic but what
the US really wants VAV India is to slow
down the growth of India's economy
India's economy is growing at a good
rate and in 20 30 years India May well
surpass
China very possible right people are
saying India will surpass China India
will surpass the US by 2075 but you know
the way things are going it could India
could be at the same rough level or even
perhaps even surpass China by 2050 or
240 or wherever whatever whichever way
you want to calculate it and that makes
India a very major world power a nuclear
armed power and all that with a big
demographic dividend and all that it's
that's that's a competitor Challenger
adversary for the US that's how they see
it so they would like to slow down
India's growth and ensure that India
stays mired in mediocrity
so that's why do they're doing all this
all all that's happening of late right
since since the Democrats came to power
2020 onwards essentially uh now
obviously then the question arises if
you do that if the Americans do this
then it kind of pushes India towards
Russia and China even more
right the point is this Russia is the
one nation the Americans genuinely fear
because of its hard military power China
is an economic giant the second largest
economy militarily it is nowhere as
capable as the us if China were so
militarily powerful and capable why
would they not take over Taiwan tomorrow
they can't even take over Taiwan which
is in their own backyard that's how
powerful the US is and India and China
have these big problems long long
lasting problems that whose roots go
back to the
1950s and now there seems to be some
kind of movement in that direction rosmo
Etc but you
know for r i to happen see RI is already
there Russia India good relations RC is
also there Russia China good relations
but IC isn't there India
China right we know that for r i to
happen India and China have to resolve
their issues now tell
me how do we resolve the issues what's
the core issue in India China the
undemarcated border between India and
India the India Tibet border
undemarcated the Chinese have
steadfastly refused to demarcate the
border now let's say there there is
let's say hypothetically there is
willingness from the Chinese side to
demarcate the Border let's say Okay
hypothetically but what is a fair
demarcation of the Border you think a
nation that's four times more powerful
than India will give back Ain and give
up its claim on
arunachal won't
happen won't happen they will lose face
terribly if they do that it'll be like
complete capitulation
so aair
realistic resolution of the boundary
dispute okay realistic non-sentimental
resolution is they keep Ain and we keep
arunachal and whatever boundary
currently exists we freeze it there and
that becomes the international
border but China can do it they are
dictatorship they are an autocracy one
party State can India do it any Indian
Prime
Minister who agrees to give up India's
claim Onin is going to lose the next
election that's a guarantee the Indian
people are hyper sentimental
hyper uh what's the
term um yeah they hyper emotional right
Indians are an extremely emotional
people they don't see things practically
realistically they see things things
through through emotions very
superficial way of looking at things
that's the majority of the Indian
population so if an Indian prime
minister AG agrees to that sort of an
arrangement he is going to lose the next
election so then the core issue between
India and China cannot be resolved even
if there's willingness on both sides so
then can RC happen I mean IC happen
India and China get along as long as the
border is not demarcated there's going
to be tensions On the Border you can
have some kind of Modas weend that we
will go easy on the patrolling and all
but that issue is the core of everything
and then there's this gigantic trade
imbalance between India and China so r i
is currently kind of a pipe dream Mr
Putin desperately wants RC to happen I
can assure you that I'm pretty certain
that he must have been a major driving
Factor be behind the current the
thoughts that we are witnessing between
India and China but it's it's far from
normal relations so the Americans know
this they know this and they would have
factored all this into their
calculations so r i is is is far from
happening we could have some kind of
modus vend between India and China but
then there's a huge imbalance trade
imbalance that we would like to see
redressed and obviously the Border
issues is the core of everything the
Chinese would like us to see past the
Border issue but we
can't so there we have it it's it's
easier said than done r
i um and look Ric becomes a danger a
dangerous factor for the US only if
there is a military Alliance and
economic Alliance is nothing the
Americans control the world's economy
they control the US dollar they own the
US dollar the the Eon iic Alliance is
nothing the real factor that matters in
geopolitics is your hard military power
and your power projection abilities
India Russia China you combine them
together what power projection abilities
do we have the Americans they they they
can project power all across the globe
they can intervene militarily
essentially anywhere on the globe at 60
minutes notice can India do that can
Russia do that can China do that
absolutely not so as long as the
competition is economic even if r i
happens economically it's not a big deal
for the US I mean they will have Ways
and Means to deal with that the real
danger is is a military alliance between
r i and that is not going to happen
anytime in the foreseeable future so so
that's the
answer
okay
uh okay what other questions do we have
look I'm not taking questions about
Indian politics okay I I don't comment
about Indian politics it's not my
um it's it's not my my my my specialty
or whatever okay I don't analyze in in
politics so I will not take questions
about that
uh NAD Goda says what about the 16
million more votes for the Democrats in
the last election where did they vanish
this
time
well when you ask this question on
Twitter there are the community notes
kicks in and it says that you know about
10 20 million votes have still not been
counted so once those are factored in
then the votes will equalize him so on
that's the kind of claim they make but I
don't see that happening at all anywhere
so let's say there are 15 16 million
votes that are
missing okay entirely missing so the
last election happened what
2019 2020 whenever it happened right
it's about four years ago during
covid so one explanation you could give
is that 15 16 million people 20 whatever
number is they died during covid but the
Americans have never reported such large
numbers of covid deaths nothing
comparable to that so then that's out of
the picture unless the Americans were
lying about covid deaths which is also
well a
possibility so either they died during
covid which is another shocking news or
well then there's no explanation except
for that
explanation yeah that the last election
was rigged so that's two op that's
two plausible explanations for the
missing gigantic chunk of votes there's
no other explanation from the way I see
it uh
yeah mcloven says why does why do
Indians still have a socialist mindset
people still have money and hate money
and rich people I suppose uh look it's
the education system it's the media it's
the entertainment industry all of that
combines together the collude to create
this mindset especially the education
system especially the
politicians you know
India's politicians I I'm not naming
anybody in particular I'm just saying on
average India's politicians are
reasonably very reasonably very wealthy
but see what kind of clothing they wear
they'll wear very shabby white clothing
they will never show off their wealth
unless they are really silly there are
few parliamentarian who do that and they
don't have a very good
image so uh there's this whole potin
poian mindset image that's been created
through Decades of the same rotten
education system movies always glorify
poverty and and suffering and getting
wethy seen as something bad and the
Indian system the Indian system for
decades has been such that until very
recently you could not get rich without
indulging in some kind of underhand
dealings right there's a time when you
had license Raj and permit Raj and
whatnot you could never get well and you
had what income tax rates at 990 5% or
whatnot so it was impossible to get
wealthy unless you were doing something
underhand so then if somebody is wealthy
people would look at that person with
justifiable suspicion that this person
obviously must be hand in glove with
various kinds of well elements let's say
yeah so that mindset still
continues and that's a terrible mindset
I think we should we should learn from
uh our Chinese friends then shopping the
great uh late leader of China said that
being rich is glorious you should aim
and aspire to be rich so uh but that
mindset is still there in India so if if
you have various uh corporations and
industrialists who get really wealthy
and with wealth comes some power then
those are ridiculed and mocked and hated
and all that I think that mindset really
really needs to go away and obviously uh
even today the the ease of doing
business is not there it's really
difficult to do business it's the tax
regime is is uh extremely painful and
all so even today it's really difficult
to get wealthy I mean you have all this
unicorns in India and all the startups
many of them go to valuations of 1
billion plus which means it's a unicorn
and they end up making big losses so
what was that value valuation all about
so people there is some justification in
the way the people are extremely
skeptical about these things so you you
have a startup you it becomes a unicorn
it's it's making losses is quarter after
quarter but after a certain period of
time you sell your shares and you retire
with your billions and then the people
the shareholders and employees they have
to face the brunt of the collapse of the
of the thing so even today you have this
happening and uh I think the government
needs to do a better job of well I would
not say regulating regulation
overregulation has always been the bane
of India but the system has to be the
right kind of climate environment Etc
has to be created that these things
don't happen and actual if if if an if a
starts startup's valuation is 1 billion
then it you can't have that valuation if
you are if you're making losses every
every every quarter and so on so there
there's all these problems that exist
which is why people are still extremely
skeptical and suspicious about people
who get rich and people who have
money so there's a lot of changes that
need to happen in in society at the
society level the media level at the tax
regime level the government level the
ease of doing business level and so many
other levels for this mindset to
overtime go away and I think we really
need to see this mindset go
away
okay Brides SK says will the Deep State
allow Donald Trump to end the war in
Ukraine where they could have ended
during the Biden Administration instead
of spending billions of dollars maybe
they have decided that now is the time
look maybe the objective of the war was
not to defeat Russia free Ukraine or
whatever H see first of all the special
military operation was not started by
the Americans by the by NATO it was
started by Putin by Russia by President
Putin and he was left with no choice but
to do this otherwise it would be like
NATO on his borders right at his borders
right at his doorstep NATO missiles at
his doorstep he couldn't let that happen
so he was forced into that if he had
been a little smarter I would say with
with the benefit of hindsight it's
easier to say this it's very easy to say
this and criticize but my point is the
right time to do that would have been
2014 when it took Crimea actually but
well that's what we can say with the
benefit of H hindsight it's not easy
being in Mr Putin's position so he
launched this special military operation
which we call the Ukraine
war and uh once this happened
obviously the US whoever runs the us
would have known that Putin will be left
with no choice but to do this and then
you do some calculations you do some War
gaming
right and uh
one of the outcomes of this war has been
the de rapid de-industrialization of
Europe northstream happened the pipeline
was blown up one of the pipelines was
blown up the second one has been shut
down right so Germany has been starved
of cheap energy Germany went to a went
into a recession and now they are not
doing well at all they've been pouring
money that is taxpayer money that is
been that is intended for German
Germany's development into Ukraine so
all the EUR essentially the whole of
Western Europe EU and NATO nations are
kind of doing very poorly right now
economically Europe is being
de-industrialized essentially the the
engine that always drove the European uh
economy was Germany and Germany is in
the doldrums right now so maybe the
objective of this entire matter the
Ukraine war of of forcing into Putin
into starting the Ukraine war was to
actually de industrialize Europe and and
turn Europe into an insignificant
geopolitical entity perhaps that was the
objective maybe that that objective was
even well it was it was bolstered by
pushing in millions of undocumented
illegal immigrants so-called refugees
into Europe certain kinds of refugees
military age males with with almost no
women and children so that is kind of
yeah and lots of essentially almost all
the EU countries have been forced into
accepting very large numbers of refugees
so Europe is in a mess right now and
maybe the point
the whole point the whole purpose of
this Ukraine thing was
to was to put Europe in this crisis and
it's a crisis that it's almost
impossible for European nations to
extricate them out of without leaving
the EU without leaving NATO and that's
not happening right so maybe the
objective has been achieved now
Ukraine's purpose has been served and
Ukraine is just a disposable Pawn on the
chessboard on the geopolitical
chessboard so now it's time to sacrifice
that pawn end of story now we will
militarize militarize
Poland so Poland is is being quietly
militarized it's becoming Europe's
primary military power so Poland could
be the the next Lynch pin for NATO so
yeah so if that is the case and the
objective has been served then it will
be okay for Donald Trump to end the war
in Ukraine and through whichever means
uh you know negotiate with Putin sit
down negotiate and come to some kind of
a deal
maybe freeze the line of control where
the Russian positions currently are the
the the front lines of the Russian
positions maybe that sort of thing or
maybe Putin will push for more and we'll
see how it goes but yeah Trump will most
likely end the war in Ukraine and
probably the Deep States agenda has been
served when it comes to
Ukraine
okay adiya
says 1.4 billion people but not a single
jet inur company s such a shame look if
India had been allowed to privatize in
1947 1950 wherever if India had been
allowed to start developing all these
Technologies back then then we would
have been in a very good position
today uh now we have the drdo which is a
government run organization that is
engaged in jet engine development the
cavar engine and its various
variants um and the place where the
research is being done is the gas
turbine research establishment GT in
bangaluru
uh now the Kary engine obviously it's
facing some problems it's it's not easy
to you know develop a world class engine
at the first try and they've been trying
for the past two three decades uh and
it's it's able to uh uh produce a Thrust
of what 70 70 odd kiltons roughly
roughly 70 kons of thust thrust and for
the LCA AES you want what 110 or
something something and the theas is a
single engine aircraft so you need just
one engine in on that that can produce
let's say give or take 100 ton 110 kons
of thrust so there's a gap of 40 kons of
thrust but if you were to have an
aircraft similar to the Rafal which is a
twin engine aircraft then you could have
two Cav engines 70 plus 70 is 140 Kon of
thrust which is quite significant I'm
sure that the rafal's engines are also
roughly like that with 70 roughly 70 or
so kiltons of thrust so I think that the
calary engine can be used for certain
purposes but the point of the question
is not that the point of qu the question
is why don't we have private companies
that develop jet engines and that's
truly remarkable that we don't have any
such thing in India well in the US we
have private companies in the UK you
have rollsroyce and so on so forth in
France you had saf which is saf which
used to be called snika the Russians
have their own things and all and we
don't so it's it's truly a shame we
should allow private I mean Private
Industry should have been allowed back
in the day to start you know developing
doing the R&D for all these things but
we never allowed that the government was
all about centralized control and
socialism and that's how we have ended
up in this in this situation jet engine
development takes
decades uh and we are at a reasonable
position maybe so that's the situation
we are in right now so what's the
solution I in my opinion the solution is
to Simply buy big borrow or steal
technology the Chinese are great at
stealing I don't blame them for that
geopolitics is all about winning okay
it's not about how you win but the fact
that you
win um so they obviously we know that
they've been they've been acquiring
technology through certain means hacking
and all that yeah so that's stealing
otherwise you buy b or borrow you can't
borrow technology you can't beg
technology you have to buy it so we
should either probably do a deal with
the French it'll be very expensive it'll
cost an arm and a leg but as long as we
get full technology transfer of a proper
high quality jet engine then we can
start iterating on that and develop you
know expanding on that and making uh you
know making various variants of that I'm
not sure where we stand in that process
but uh it is also very good idea to have
private players enter this field jet
engine technology is very difficult
because the the turbine BL blades need
to withstand
incredibly high temperatures and
pressures at which typically metal
becomes soup right but these blades have
to withstand those pressures and they
have to work for thousands of hours at
these temperatures and pressures before
you overhaul the Jet
Engine and that's and to do that you
have to have single Crystal
monocrystalline blades and that's a and
you need to have all kinds of air
cooling systems inside the blades and so
on it's extremely complicated it takes
time it takes decades to develop that so
best best solution for India right now
is to just buy the technology whatever
it
costs so
um do it how long does it take to buy
it just ask the price and pay it I mean
it's not like we don't have money so
yeah the government needs to take a call
maybe in the next decade or two
hopefully
manushi says how did Byron become well
all of a sudden so the past four years
he's been not entirely present right he
appears on stage and stumbles and
mumbles and shakes hands with invisible
people and gets lost where do I go here
there sometimes he says words that are
completely incoherent
and yeah but suddenly after after the
elections results came out he comes on
stage and gives an address and is all
crisp and clear and precise and not a
single fumble what happened all of a
sudden uh so maybe it something to do
with the fact that the there was a coup
against Biden okay there was a
republican sorry democ in the Democratic
party they essentially pushed him out
they shoved him out of the
race the incumbent president who has
served one term could be the next
presidential candidate but they shoved
him out obviously he's of advanced age
and all that but that's okay even Trump
is 78 isn't he so they shoved him out
and apparently what the Democrats wanted
was to hold a primary a primary is an
internal election in which the next
presidential candidate is uh
elected but the moment Biden was shoved
out within 30 minutes of that happening
he endorsed Kamala Harris an official
presidential endorsement of Kamala
Harris which left the Democrats with no
choice but to accept Kamal Harris as
their next presidential candidate
without holding a
primary so Biden counter CED them he was
CED out and he counter coed them he
placed that Uno reverse he played that
Uno reverse card on them and then they
had to accept Kamala as their
presidential candidate
and we knew everyone knew how that would
end right and there was this a few a
couple of months ago or whenever Biden
actually put on a Maga hat make America
greater again that's that's the Trump
hat the red red hat and he put that on
in in some kind of public appearance
that was curious and then on the day of
the election when everyone was going out
to vote his wife the first lady Jill
Biden she put on a dress that was full
Maga
red so it appears that both of them
voted for trump it looks like and uh
once the election results are out
everyone looks unhappy among the
Democrats and he is all cheerful and
chirpy and all Sharp all 100% there wow
so yeah he gave it back to them they Eed
him they shoved him out and he shoved
them out of the race that's what he did
that's what it looks like okay we don't
have any confirmation of these things
these things are never confirmed or
denied but that's what it looks
like okay
um ronit who says do you think research
papers on History Science and Etc can be
manipulated to serve agenda like media
Etc and if yes how can we know anything
is
true well well well well well
yes yes history papers can be
manipulated okay let's talk about
history
first history papers can be
manipulated what you do is this you have
your selected historians who are in
positions in the top universities in
your country let's say we talking about
India for example so there will be in
jnu in various other institutions
universities and in the humanities in
the history departments there is a
strangle hold of the left so they'll all
have a certain agenda now let's say they
want to construct some kind of narrative
about Indian history right
so they will have somebody write a
research paper one person with a very
spirous
conclusion fake history like you have
fake news they'll write paper which has
fake history one paper
and then that paper will somehow get
published in a research journal for
example
okay for instance right now there's this
Manipur crisis happening right and there
is this alleged Anglo cookie War
apparently that happened no such War
happened okay the cookies were on the
side of the of the anglos of the British
occupiers of India they were their
servants but apparently nowadays there
is this claim that there was an Anglo
cooki war that happen so how do you make
this apparently a reality you have
somebody write a research paper about
this fake war and it somehow gets
published in some Journal then you have
10 more researchers site that paper and
write more papers about this so-called
Anglo cooki war and then you force
students who are doing their PHD to site
those papers those 10 11 papers and then
after a few years you have hundreds of
papers that are all based on one initial
fake history paper and that's how you
manufacture fake history and then it
becomes then it gets cited in books and
you can write books about this and you
can do PhD thesis on these things and
that's how fake history gets
manufactured I'm just giving one example
of this fake Angi War which never
happened but we know that our entire
history has been misrepresented by our
by our
historians that orb was a saint and
whatnot right the British were they came
here to to serve India and they did so
much great things so many good things
for India and so on so forth and certain
compromised traitors were actually great
freedom for Freedom Fighters allegedly
so you manufacture fake history like
this so of course history history
research papers can be manipulated when
it comes to science it's a little more
difficult
but there is what what do you call the
the replication crisis in science so a
significant percentage of research
papers on scientific subjects and
Technical subjects engineering Etc
applied science whatever they can't be
replicated the results of these papers
are not replicable which means that
these papers are
spurious that there's a replication
crisis in science right now so even that
can't be trusted these
days fortunately the kind of science I'm
into is pure theoretical physics which
is very hard to well in that case
there's no replication of theories of
course the theories obviously eventually
have to yield uh predictions and those
predictions can be tested uh and right
now we are at a crisis in physics also
that's a whole different thing but when
it comes to Science Biology biochemistry
nanotchnology uh
semiconducting um genetics Etc there's a
replication crisis and let let's not
even speak about the Corona virus shall
we so today so many scientists are
compromised that it's very hard
to believe them and to believe that
research it doesn't mean science is
wrong it means those people are
compromised and those those research
journals are compromised and the whole
system is
compromised there's a lack of academic
Integrity it doesn't mean there's a
problem with science there's a problem
with these individuals who claim to be
scientists and that's why so many
scientists are escaping from Academia
and going into various
industries that that's the crisis you're
facing
so uh and and if you and this has been
around for a very long time let's talk
about the US okay there was a time in
the 1950s 60s Etc when doctors Doctors
medical doctors who had taken the
hypocritic oath to do no harm they used
to endorse cigarette
brands cigarette brands I mean you can
look it up on Google they used to
endorse cigarette brands they used to
even Endor cigarettes that had asbestos
filters as asbestos plus I mean tobacco
itself is harmful enough now you making
people inhale asbestos fibers asbestos
causes m misoa in various kinds of it's
a kind of cancer extraordinarily
aggressive form of cancer that affects
the lungs apparently lungs I think yeah
so that's the kind of thing you had and
then the the uh the American diet right
which is approved by the FDA or whatever
right the Surgeon General and whatnot
the American diet is a tremendous amount
of the official government mandated
government sanctioned American diet it
places a tremendous amount of emphasis
on processed carbohydrates you know how
people get fat and obese not by eating
fat you get fat and obes by eating
processed carbohydrates in large
quantities and the more you eat you eat
that the more you crave
that pasta and Breads and
whatnot H and all that is mandated and
and and sugar is apparently good sugar
is what causes most of these problems
sugar causes
cancers cancer cells feed on sugar
glucose you starve the body of sugar
cancer cells can't replicate and
Thrive so there's so much manipulation
that has happened which is why people no
longer trust science and then this the
these people they say trust the science
science is not about trusting science is
never about trust science is about
skeptic I ISM science is about is about
questioning don't trust the science
question the science that's how
scientific progress happens if you don't
question the status quo you'll never
have progress in science how did quantum
mechanics come about how did everything
come about all the all the technological
advances and all that through
questioning through through being by
being
skeptical how dare you question Isaac
newon because because you should
question everything in India with the
situ the the the mindset is that you
can't question people in
Authority don't question what's in the
textbooks low IQ Behavior right you have
to constantly reassess what's
happening so what if your great
professor said something he or she could
be wrong so that's the problem and
that's why people are finding it
increasingly difficult to trust the
science trust history trust the news
trust anything because everything is
propaganda that's the sad State of
Affairs maybe India should take the lead
and clean up the academic system I've
been saying this for how many
years am I an enemy of
India am I not a wellwisher of my
country my civilization my people but
no I I guess I'll just keep it keep keep
on saying it until my last day please
reform the education system please
reform Academia but not happening not
happening
sad
okay honey says how about we keep axin
as no man's land we haven't seen the map
today how how can you have asked amij
without seeing the map okay let us go to
map yes shall we and we're talking about
aai chin so here we have the map and
India is as always as usual in the
center now we go to the northern part of
India and we're talking about
ladak and we're talking about this
particular portion of ladak which is in
the center of your screen right now okay
that is currently up to Goa Etc
so so significant portion of this region
of ladak is under currently under
Chinese control and occupation okay that
gigantic piece of territory is axin what
are the dimensions of axin let's let's
try and find out the dimensions
blah so it's a
trapezoid 600 time 400 or
something it's about you could say
about 2,000 square kilometers maybe more
than that so that's a gigantic piece of
real estate there are countries that are
smaller than that it's gigantic it's
huge and it is
valuable how is it valuable because
didn't the great Shri nehu G the
Magnificent Mr Neu say that not a blade
of grass grows there who cares about
that Barren piece of high altitude
desert where the temperatures are
frighteningly shocking - 20 -30 -4
who cares about that Barren piece of
land well nothing grows there so how is
it valuable I'm making the claim that
it's
valuable mineral resources natural use
resources you know what
else
uranium
uranium why would somebody give that
up why would they agree to make it no
man's land first of all it is larger
than a lot of Nations that's how big it
is no man's land is typically a small
sliver of land between two Nations if
there is some dispute or whatever that's
it's typically half a kilometer 1 kilom
maybe 5 kilometers in
width it can be
gigantic and it has such incredible
natural resources why would anybody Give
It Away whoever is in possession would
never give it away and you have Chinese
roads that go through this piece of
Territory Road a road that was built in
the 1950s and Mr n did not know about it
for 2 years 3 years whatever
so it's not going to happen I mean I
know you're trying to creatively find
Solutions which we really appreciate we
all need to look at try and find
Solutions and then propose Solutions so
good job at that but unfortunately it's
not going to work out that way because
it's too valuable a piece of real estate
a piece of territory too
valuable
okay um cek India says will Ukraine and
Russia reunify in the century or the
USSR become
one come into existence again look I am
not a fortune teller astrologer
um what what are the conditions that
could lead to the reunification of
Russia and Ukraine look they are both
Slavic Nations the languages are very
similar the cultures are very similar
Ukraine used to be part of Russia it was
called Noosa it was called ukraina which
means the Borderlands the Borderlands of
what of Russia obviously the Russian
Empire so it was always part of Russia
historically but because of various
reasons it's currently a separ
Nation reunification will be difficult
for some time because there's a lot of
antipathy among the Ukrainian population
towards Russia maybe some of that from
the Russian side perhaps to a lesser
extent perhaps and obviously uh you have
a regime in power in Kev which is very
very strongly anti- Russia because it's
a puppet regime of the West right it
this regime is a continuation of the
regime that came to power in 2014 in the
euroman coup which was a coup against
the elected constitutionally elected
government of Ukraine so Ukraine is a
western puppet why would uh the West
give up give up their hold on whatever
is left of Ukraine so I think right now
it's not possible maybe maybe in the
future if there's a geopolitical
realignment and the West becomes
slightly weaker and Russia becomes
somewhat stronger it could happen um but
not in the immediate short to
medium-term Future not the next 10 20
years perhaps who knows I may be wrong
but I am no fortune teller I not an
astrologer I don't make such predictions
so I think right now now it's rather
unlikely for that to happen in the
near-term
future
okay prank two says do you think that
when the British conducted literary
literacy surveys in India they only
considered those who can read and write
in the English language
literate look that's an interesting
question uh their objective was to have
uh
English language education become pre
prevalent all across India and their
objective is now coming
true because of the efforts ceaseless
tireless efforts of the government of
India making English compulsory
mandatory in various States and whatnot
incredibly shortsighted and regressive
and and and counterproductive policies
but what can I say now coming back to
the question um we know for a fact that
uh this is right called dhal right who
collated all the data the statistical
data and analytical data that the
British had
produced across India of of Education of
the Indian education system and through
that he was able to show that all of
these myths about Indian education are
false that girls were left out that
certain casts were not given education
that and so on he he discovered through
the British data that there was
education was prevalent all across India
in temples were the places where
education actually happened at at the
Grassroots level temples were temples
were centers of Education that's why we
and we had temples all across India tens
of hundreds of thousands of temples all
across India much of it is gone today
wonderful no no
nice so the British did conduct these
surveys and they did collect all this
information about the Indian education
system the indigenous education system
in in the medium of education education
was either the mother tongue or son
especially at the higher levels when you
get went to higher education if you
wanted that then you would definitely
have Sanskrit as as a medium of
Education especially for certain aspects
of Education um so at at least in the
19th century when they were doing these
surveys they did not consider people to
be literate only if they could read and
write in
English right so that's what I can tell
you afterwards I don't know what their
attitude was but their objective was
certainly to angiz India to deracinate
India and they to a large extent failed
at that but today they are succeeding
that project is still in Motion in India
today because you're not literate unless
you speak good English with a certain
accent right if you speak with a daisy
accent you are not literate you're very
backward and that's how it is and that's
a very unfortunate situation we have in
India but the government is exacerbating
this by by making English English
language uh English the study of English
and English language education kind of
the norm in a lot of states which is
extremely uh problematic problematic
yes okay m l asks me a question to which
I don't know the answer what is the
mystery of The Wallace Line I'm not
aware of it sorry you see I yeah I I
don't know what that is maybe I could do
a Google search but then I'm not giving
you an answer it's Google that's giving
you the answer so I apologize I don't
have the answer to this I am not aware
of this Wallace
Line okay
Billy AK says I don't like buying and
reading books but I like to read about
history a lot so which trusted online
sources would you suggest to read about
Indian history well that's a really
difficult question to answer there is no
trustable Source trusted Source no
reliable source anywhere about Indian
history even the books that I have I
mean these are all science books but I
have a whole bunch of history books as
well every single book that I have read
about Indian history even written by
really good authors contains some
distortions and some fake
history RC majumdar is the creator of
the term brahminism what the hell is
brahminism
it's Hinduism right I mean the Hindu
dharm sanatan DH what is brahminism that
person who is one of the best history
authors that we have today came up with
that horrific term that is now used by
leftists to they they will not attack
Hinduism they will attack brahminism
which is a dog whistle for Hindu phobia
so this guy RC majar came up with this
term brahminism at least he's the his
books are the oldest books that I know
of in which I found this term I don't
know if somebody else came up with it
before him but these are the oldest
books in which I found this term
brahminism and
brahminical so even in the best of books
written by the best of authors you will
find all kinds of distortions every book
you will have the Aran Invasion lie the
Aran Invasion migration tourism picnic
myth that will be baked into it and a
lot of the times you find that these
authors actually had good intentions and
they actually truly believe believe that
this Invasion happened well if you are a
historian should you not look for
evidence that okay let's say an Aran
invasion is postulated to have happened
where's the evidence is there any
evidence of Iran invasion was there any
such thing during R majas time then why
did he write about the AR Invasion even
though there was no evidence so that
raises a lot of questions so my point is
there is no author I can recommend no
book I can recommend that is
reliable especially for a
beginner if you are a seasoned student
of History then you will immediately
recognize where the flaws and
distortions and the lies
are but if you are a beginner you'll
just absorb it
wholesale so I I am that's why I am so
loath to recommend
anything how did I study history look a
lot
of significant portion of the time
especially as a kid as a teen Etc I was
just reading about world history I had
no interest in Indian history Indian
history was depressing as hell for me
it's all
about invasions and OCC foreign
occupation and massacres and genocide
and sad stories and and defeats I don't
enjoy that so I I stayed away from indan
industry but eventually I kind of got
interested through a variety of ways
trying to understand what was what's my
origin my particular lineage what's the
origin what are the roots and so on so
that's how I kind of got into it and I
read a lot from so many different online
sources sources that no longer even
exist um I read a lot of research papers
diving deep into rabbit holes into very
specific minute topics and over time all
of that built up and it built up my big
picture of History so I would say that
if you are capable of reading actual
research papers and research journals
which have very academic dry dense
terminology then if you if you are
capable of that if you can handle that
you should do that but you say that you
don't really like reading in okay it's
not books it's research papers I'm
referring to there are lots of History
journals and all academic journals even
there you will have lies
obviously so that's the thing you know
it's it's really hard very difficult and
very dangerous for me to recommend
anything because people will then say
that abijit you gave us the wrong
sources
um so I would say read RC majar but you
don't like books I don't know I don't
know my only solution is read actual
research papers diving deep into various
topics if you if you can handle that do
a lot of that and then you will start
understanding history uh that's what I
could
say Okay sidhar says I read an article
titled the pentagon's secret plans to
secure Pakistan's nuclear Arsenal why
would the US try to do that if they are
the ones who help them and can't they do
that
easily okay yeah it's true that the West
the Americans the Americans control the
West the West is uh the the source of
Pakistan's nuclear program uh what was
that guy's name AQ Khan Abdul Kadir Khan
or whatever his name was he stole some
blueprints from the Netherlands or
whatever for
making U uranium centrifuges and all the
uranium hexafluoride centrifuges and
whatever and then they got some aid from
the Chinese as well some Korean missile
designs and apparently the Chinese
tested a couple of Pakistani or a few
Pakistani nuclear devices in the lnor
region and so
on but uh the West wanted Pakistan to
have nuclear weapons because India had
tested a nuke in 1974 and then India
went to sleep after that we have
demonstrated our technological progress
and then now we'll go to sleep it's only
until it was only when vajpai Mr vajpai
came to power in that India did a new
series of tests in 98 and then said that
we now have a nuclear Doctrine and a
nuclear program and it's going to be
part of our military
considerations uh but the Americans
always wanted to counterbalance India
and that's why they allowed the
pakistanis to acquire nukes now so
you've read this thing I I am not aware
of this paper this article but uh I sure
there is concern within various circles
in the US about the Safety and Security
of the pakist nukes the nuclear warheads
so the nuclear warheads in Pakistan are
under the control of the Pakistani
military obviously naturally right um
are they kept disassembled are they are
a few of them kept M to to to missiles
we don't know obviously they will not
publicize such information but the the
the
fear always when it comes to Pakistan is
the unpredictability of the Pakistani
military establishment there are lots of
radical elements within the mil
establishments military establishment
there may be uh people who are playing a
double game maybe people with uh
allegiances to other powers maybe people
with allegiance to Allegiance and
allegiance to Afghanistan perhaps and so
on and there are so many terrorist
outfits in Pakistan you can't even count
them you know every every District would
have three or four homegrown terrorist
outfits I'm sure that's the kind of
situation Pakistan has so the the fear
is some of these nukes if they go lose
and and they come fall into the hands of
of some terrorist outfit or whatever
then they could unleash Mayhem whenever
that's the fear so uh that's why the US
would want to have a tight leash on the
Pakistani nukes and right now Pakistan
has once again become a US vasal state
since 2022 since the out of Imran Khan
so the Americans would have a tight Hold
On
Tight at least some kind of idea of
where the nukes are and and what they're
being what is the current situation
status the current status of the
nukes and and the fear always is that
despite their best efforts what if
Pakistan disintegrates for whatever
reason maybe there's just this the
people get fed up and there's a riot
Revolution on the streets of Pakistan
and let's say the military loses power
I'm sure the military would do terrible
things before they lose power but let's
say the military loses power then what
happens to those nuclear
weapons that's always the question and
they they will have contingency plans
for these for these
eventualities so these contingency plans
will be secure so this article maybe is
referencing some secret plans but if the
plans are secret top secret or whatever
they will
not be made available to whoever writes
articles so maybe it's speculation but
the fear is that these L nukes could go
loose and they could fall into the hands
of non-government actors like we like
they call them and then they could be
turned against whoever they don't care
if India is nuked but they would be
afraid of other things like
us
uh it being it being used against the
west of the US let's say you have a nuke
that goes lose and then you have
refugees flowing in from Afghanistan or
Pakistan or wherever into Europe and
maybe somehow they're able to smuggle in
a nuke or so or just some amount of
uranium let's say and then you can use
it as in a dirty bomb which is a
horrific thing you know so on so there
there's the the Spectre of all kinds of
disastrous things that could happen and
that's why the Americans are really
concerned about the the security of
Pakistan's nuclear
warheads
okay I think I've taken this question
before vikam Vikram Ador asks and I'll
take it again obviously um why are Latin
American countries geopolitically
insignificant it's because they have no
hard power no hard power
whatsoever U the Americans in case
you're not aware they had something
called
the the Monro Doctrine
okay that goes back more than a century
so the Monro Doctrine said that European
powers will not be allowed to interfere
in the internal affairs of Any Nation in
the Americas North North America or
South America and this was initially
enforced by the British who were
America's allies at the
time um and then the Americans became
strong and powerful enough and then they
started enforcing it themselves so the
the fact of the matter is that every
single Latin American country let's go
to the map where's the map every single
nation in the Americas from the southern
tip all the way to the northern tip
every single nation is a us wasal it's a
US Clan State it's a US puppet and the
Americans have used all kinds of means
of of of U establishing and maintaining
their hold on these nations and Colombia
unfortunately regrettably was known for
the drug cartels the medine medine
cartel the K cartel and so
on and a lot of the drug trade came into
the US Mexico has its own drug problem
apparently all these problems are
control created by certain agencies
threel agencies and so on so none of the
nations in Latin America are genuinely
Sovereign they are all kind of under Us
control in very ways you know in today's
world you don't need to militarily
occupy a nation or physically colonize
it you can colonize it by remote control
just the way the entirety of the African
continent is still colonized without
anyone realizing it so all these
nations first of all they have small
economies okay the economic power of
these nations is is quite small nothing
significant I can't think of any Nation
apart from Brazil that could be in the
top 10 economies in the world and
Brazil's economy has its own spec
specific and special
problems um the ease of doing business
is terrible in South America and
secondly none of these nations is a
military power of any note take the
example of Argentina the the Argentine
government claims sovereignty over the
Faulkland Islands now as you can see
geographically the faulin islands are
kind of in a in in Argentina's
neighborhood but but who occupies and
controls the fauland islands the United
Kingdom sitting thousands of kilometers
away so Argentina isn't militarily
powerful enough to dislodge the UK from
here so as you can see and the Brazilian
police is reasonably strong but the
military I don't know how strong it is I
don't think it is strong at all you can
take a guesstimate of a nation's
military strength by looking at its
military budget so when you have you
know in your hard power is the
essentially you can calculate it by
factoring in economic strength and
military strength and when you have none
of that you're not significant at all
especially when you
are well when you are controlled by
another Nation so that's why these
nations are geopolitically
insignificant uh XE says how is Trump
winning the US elections going to impact
the war in Ukraine in Europe uh most
likely you're going to
have a negotiated settlement and and end
of the war in
Ukraine Trump is not going to allow any
more uh NATO money EU money or
especially American money to flow into
Ukraine so the war in Ukraine will end
sooner or later and they will negotiate
with the Russians and find some kind of
settlement border demarcation and all
that the Russians obviously will not
withdraw from the territories they
currently control the shoria region um
Lans donet and all that you know the the
donbas region Crimea and they want
withdraw from that why the hell would
they so I think that's where the Border
kind of the the line of control will be
demarcated and uh certain conditions
will be met hopefully and the war in
Ukraine will
end and that's what is going to happen
most likely and it will influence Europe
in a variety of ways now Poland will
become the Lynch pin of the the next
line of defense against Russia and
Poland will be militarized even more
than it is right now and the European
economy will keep on not doing well so
that's the kind of impact we're going to
have um
okay okay uh does the US have power or
any hard military in the other top four
countries like India China or Russia no
no India China Russia apart from the US
are the the only only four genuinely
Sovereign nations in the world every
other nation has less than optimal
sovereignty if if one means full
sovereignty then only the US India China
and Russia have a score of one
sovereignty score of one every other
nation has a sovereignty score less than
one Japan for example unfortunately has
a score of zero it is not sovereign it's
under military occupation but the
Americans have no military presence in
India China or Russia they can't and and
so on so yeah the Americans don't have
such a presence in these four
countries okay johnv says can we get an
understanding China series just like
you're doing understanding America
because only a handful of people talk
about China yeah I would love to but it
can't happen at the same time I'm doing
understanding America because the
understanding America project is going
to be an extremely big project is going
to take up a lot of my time so uh once
that's over I I could take up
understanding China but right now my
whole focus is going to be on
understanding America every episode will
give you a lot of information that I
have never spoken about before is going
to be based on reading a 100 books ex
extremely well reviewed books written by
American and Western authors one book A
Week essentially or sometimes one book
will be broken up into two three weeks
because some books are really
information dense and you can't gloss
over a lot of the facts so it's going to
involve a lot of work from me so I won't
be able to take up another project like
that at the same time but once once this
project is over whenever it is it'll
take at least two years I could take up
understanding China or something but
thank you for thank you for the
suggestion I appreciate that and it's
something that is
certainly something that needs to be
done for
sure somy Janes says why do Latinos look
so similar to Indians okay good question
let's go to the map so we're talking
about Latin America right uh now see
here we have India and India is located
between the
36 37 latitude and latitude let's say
excuse me
7 now if you go to South
America the same latitudes you'll you'll
find uh in miso America which is the
central part of America Mexico and all
the way up to up to let's
say uh Colombia Surinam Etc Venezuela so
people in these this part of the
American
will have essentially the same climate
as India and therefore their skin color
skin skin tones Etc will be very
similar so if you go to Mexico you will
find that most people look just like you
just like Indians and in the
US white people often mistake Americans
mistake Indians for Mexicans it's it's
known to happen Okay so that's one
reason and the native people of of of uh
the Americas are all brown skinned
people the Native Americans and a lot of
them still have a significant presence
especially in South America Latin
America in Nations for example in Brazil
you have a lot of indigenous tribes you
also have a lot of descendants of
European occupiers that's bound to
happen same thing in Argentina I
remember when D maruna he went to play
for napoi I think he went to play for
napoi was
it uh
he he played for which team I think it
was I forget which team he played for in
Italy but uh initially they used to they
used to taunt him by calling him Indian
Indian Indian means Native American it's
only after he showed his incredible
prowess that they adopted him as one of
their own but dieo Marana also has some
native blood you can see that in his
facial features the late dieo Maradona
who passed away some time ago a couple
of years ago or something so the people
the Latino people they have mixed
ancestry a lot of them have uh Native
indigenous American ancestry those
people were brown skinned not white
skinned some of them are mixed with the
descendants of European occupiers and
some of them are descendants of people
of African origin as well a lot of
people in Brazil are descended from
African slaves and then they there is
intermingling of people and then when
black white brown intermingle and then
the result is of shade of some shade of
brown so that's why a lot of Latinos
look very similar to Indians and when it
comes to places like Mexico Etc even the
cuisine is very similar to Indian Indian
Cuisine the tastes are similar the kind
of chilies they use of course the
Chili's the the peppers Chili Peppers
they came from South America and I think
the Portuguese or whoever brought them
into India before that we in India used
to uh use Peppers pepper corns black and
green peppers for spicy Cuisine for for
making your our Cuisine spicy so a lot
to unpack in there but very interesting
question
yes
okay okay Arin shuu says um Will trump
and Will trump end Muhammad yun's regime
love from Bangladesh thank you so much
love from India I don't think Trump will
end the regime of Muhammad Unos that
would go against the the interests of uh
what we call the Deep
State um so uh Trump May apply some
pressure on the Muhammad unus regime to
perhaps um end the reign of terror
against the minorities the Hindus
especially right now there's a
tremendous amount of all that happening
you know this there pograms happening
against Hindus right now we are sitting
wherever we are in in peace in comfort
and in Bangladesh there's a r reign of
terror that's been Unleashed on Hindus
and Trump trump tweeted about this he
spoke about he said that he condemns the
barbaric violence against Hindus and
other minorities in
Bangladesh um so probably when he comes
to when he actually takes over power in
January he could apply pressure on the
unus regime to end that reign of terror
against the minorities especially the
Hindus I'm sure Mr mod would have spoken
with Mr Trump about this Mr Modi was one
of the first world leaders to speak with
Mr Trump after Mr Trump got elected
after he won the election so that could
happen but I do not see Muhammad unus is
his regime
being being uh ousted by Trump or by the
US that won't happen because it does not
serve the American
interest uh even if he may be friendly
towards India having a puppet government
in
Bangladesh is is great for the US it
allows them it gives them way more
leverage over India so why would you
give that up so that won't
happen
[Music]
um okay let's see what else we have
Muhammad ISM says why do you call
American proxies terrorists but not the
big daddy funding them because one has
to be very
careful one has to be practical and
realistic yes we know that the Americans
funded Pakistani terrorism in India
against India for
decades we know that Isis was most
likely created by the Americans and so
so many other things they've done but
one has to be careful when talking about
the most powerful nation in the world
it's not a question of being a coward or
whatever it's a question of being
prudent and
realistic so there's your answer
sir RMS says can India reach 10 trillion
by 2032 I'll have to do some
calculations it may be possible at a
certain uh GDP rate of
growth uh it's it's certainly possible
yeah see right now we are what four
roughly $4 trillion GDP I have to pull
out a calculator and do all that but I
I'm sure it's possible by 203 to 2035
you know uh and it also depends on the
US dollar versus Indian rupe exchange
rate that is also something that's very
important that's also going to be a very
important factor if the Indian rupee
appreciates against the US dollar you
will reach 10 trillion very rapidly so a
lot of factors go into this we cannot
assume that we will always have the same
exchange rate that we currently have
Visa the dollar So Many Factors go to
this
okay mlen says hypothetically if vac
ramasami is our agent and becomes SPS
what can he do in his power for India
absolutely nothing he's not our agent
and I'm not sure if he'll become pors
and even if he becomes sporters he's
going to be the president of the United
States in that hypothetical scenario and
he will serve serve the nation of his
birth and the nation for which he whose
citizenship he has he won't do a thing
for India he may be more favorably
inclined towards India in certain ways
more friendly and overall relations may
be better for four years or whatever
time period that he president but he
won't do anything for India he will do
whatever he does for the
US
okay now
ishan chatur says most intelligent book
you ever read well that's
interesting I would have to go into the
realm of Science and
physics I would say uh good back is a
good book oh let's let's Google it so
that you also can know what that is yeah
just give me a second let's go to Google
it's a really difficult book to
understand I would say for most people
but let's go there
isue and back by diglas hofstad that's a
really profound book okay then there is
penrose's book The Road to Reality
Penrose Roger Penrose Road to Reality
that's a pretty good
book uh pretty intelligent what else
what else what other books could I think
of uh where's
the David D
books yeah so the beginning of infinity
is a very profound book really really
interesting really profound very
intelligent definitely that and what
else I don't know if you if you put me
in the spot like this it's uh hard for
me to remember on the spot I've read so
many books and
um um apart from that
what i' rather not recommend books about
hard science hard physics because there
are many really intelligent books that
you get
there um yeah so maybe you could take a
look at those books those
are pretty intelligent hard reads
difficult reads but yeah if you can read
that over time you will gain a thing or
two for
sure um lucky AA says do you go do you
see India going to war in the near
future you know on the one hand I don't
want to see India go to war on the other
hand you know it's very counterintuitive
but Wars are good for Nations they
Harden Nations you know what a war does
first of all it trims out all the fat
from the military if your nation is at
War and you you have your armed forces
in that hypothetical theoretical
scenario fighting a war on the front
lines you're going to have attri on the
battlefield people will get knocked out
of action right
casualties when you have casualties you
have field promotions on the battlefield
and Battlefield promotions are always
based on Merit not on
seniority so Battlefield promotions will
give you a really hard and capable
leadership but that only happens in
Warfare when you have a war a nation at
War your entire economy gears towards
War you have to cut out all the all the
nonsense all the all the BS all the flab
you have to you to gear the entire
economy towards the war effort it also
uh reorients kind of magnetizes society
in in a certain way all the all the
traitors are exposed very rapidly and
then well whatever right so in a way a
war makes keeps a n nation that goes to
war on a let's say frequent basis it's
generally a much harder leaner meaner
nation and it has a way more way much
more
higher nationalistic Outlook among its
population nationalism is not being
patriotic is not about raising slogans I
love my country I will give my life for
my country I support our Armed Forces
all that is just
sloganeering you have to be patriotic
with your actions in various ways that's
what happens when you have an actual war
going on so in one of the Nations that's
always at War essentially is the US and
you can see it's it's got a very hard
Edge because of
that and in the past you had the UK that
was always at War it was always
expanding colonizing it had a very hard
Edge
Russia has seen tremendous amount of
warfare Russia has a very hard Edge uh
when was the last time India was at War
we had a very limited War the Cargill
War whenever it was 98
or 2001 whichever year it was before
that we had 71 but after that we've not
had a war I mean look I'm not saying I'm
not I'm not being a warmonger I'm not
advocating going to war war is obviously
terrible we would like to see peace
but of looking at this thing from a
certain perspective war is not entirely
a bad thing from a certain perspective
war is terrible for
civilians War has all kinds of suffering
human suffering
terrible but macro level Wars can be
good for countries that's the
Paradox that we
face um but I would say that I would I
rather hope that India does not go to
war in the near future because it will
be bad perhaps most likely bad for our
economy and uh yeah we would like to
have peace for the next 20 years minimum
so that we can fully build up the
economy and and another advantage of war
is that you
know is
that the nation a nation that's at War
doesn't tolerate soft leadership
hopefully otherwise you lose otherwise
you lose you end up losing you become a
loser so a leader that's weak is is
hopefully shoved out and and a really
hard-edged leader comes to power which
is good for a nation so uh those are the
advantages of a Nation being at War a
lot of the time but we don't want to be
in that position right now we need a lot
of reforms in the country we need our
economy to grow for that we would not
want to go to war so I hope India
doesn't go to war for the next 20 years
minimum and right now it doesn't look
like there's going to be a scenario in
the near to medium-term Future where we
go to war so hopefully it stays that
way okay uhti says pronam uh should
India procure more new H made super suo
to counter falling Squad numbers we have
the production capability and super suo
um I'm not sure how much of the super
suko or the Suk 30
mki uh it's how much of it is indigenous
I I believe that we receive these kits
from Russia and we assemble the kits in
the H and I'm sure there's a lot of
indigenization that's happened over the
years and a lot of the parts would be
made in India but the core Technologies
would still be controlled by Russia I'm
sure and I'm sure the Russians would be
okay with us producing let's say 300
more Super suis or whatever they'll be
okay with that and they won't come in
the way but is that what we
need is that what we need is that truly
an Indian
aircraft uh and do we have the
capability the capacity to to churn out
a large number of these aircraft every
year I mean H has always had these
issues with production
lines we were producing what 16 tagious
Fighters a year and that even that has
been now stalled because the Americans
are not sending us not not uh supplying
us the fighter uh
the jet engines the what 404 or whatever
jet engine right they not supplying
these jet engines so we are stalled
right now um so in case HL has the
capability capacity to churn out a large
number of the soo every year at least 20
30 then maybe you should do that so in
five years if if you're doing 20 year
then in five years you have 100 and
what's the Squadron 18 I don't know what
the squad number is but yeah it could
really help us out that's one thing we
could do or then the other option is we
set up a manufacturing line
manufacturing line of the Rafal in India
and procure 100 200 of those which will
cost us an arm and a leg but what to
do uh and of course of course we are
going ahead with the development of the
um
pages mark 2 or whatever in the amca
perhaps the fgfa whatever these aircraft
and that should continue in the
meanwhile for as a stop cap solution
maybe we could do something like this uh
so I think the super suko could be a low
hanging fruit it will be something that
can be easily achieved if that's what we
want to do is that what our Air Force
requires I think numbers really matter
the sukko is a good aircraft so maybe we
can go for that but at the end of the
day at the end of the day the government
makes these
decisions okay hany Sharma says then
what do you propose I mean excuse me
what it's in response to which answer I
already answered a whole bunch of
questions and Why Us offers to moderate
the Border dispute to end tensions
between whom India Pakistan India China
who the US has no business interceding
between India and China the Chinese want
listen to the
Americans and I knew about the road but
they didn't do anything about it because
they didn't want to trigger the Chinese
I'm not sure what you're asking
sir are you asking about what do I
propose about the resolution of the
boundary dispute between India and China
I would propose I would say that the the
realistic solution is to freeze the
Border where it is which means India
gives up any more claims on aai chin
swallow the bitter pill and China gives
up its claims on whatever territory they
are claiming arunachal Pradesh Etc and
they give up their claims on whatever
bhutan's territory they're claiming I
think that is a practical feasible
solution it will require a climb down of
kinds of sorts from both
sides and just freeze the B where it is
that is the solution I would propose but
uh I would say the majority of Indians
will Heap abuses on me for that because
I'm saying that we should give upin give
up the claim on ayin the Chinese will
never return Ain to India they are way
more powerful than us and no powerful
Nation gives up territory to a weaker
Nation please understand and accept the
fact that today 2024 November whatever
date it is today India is weaker than
China significantly weaker than China
and as such we cannot expect them to
give up our territory even though it is
justifiably our territory or whatever
there's no justice in the world world
the only thing that matters in the world
is leverage and power and strength and
the Chinese have that we don't so the
best possible solution right now is to
freeze the Border where it is in 100
years in 50 years we'll see right now
freeze it here and end the end the
problem that's what I propose I don't
know what the Americans are proposing or
what not they they don't have any
business coming in this interfering in
this matter this is a bilateral issue
between India and China the Americans
have no business offering to moderate or
whatever okay stay out of this matter
that's what I would say to the Americans
intelligence Bureau knew about the road
they didn't do anything because they
didn't want to Trigg the intelligence
Bureau my friend reports to
whom who's at the
top Mr Prime Minister yes and I'm pretty
sure that Mr Nero was told about this
and he kept quiet eventually the matter
was raised in Parliament before it was
RA see when the matter was raised in
Parliament about this Chinese Road in
the 1950s through aai
chin
so about 2 or three years had passed
since the Chinese had built constructed
the road and only two three years later
was the matter raised in Parliament and
then Mr Neu said how does it matter not
a single blade of grass grows there but
I am sure that much before the
Parliamentary question the question in
Parliament much before that I'm sure the
intelligence Bureau and whoever else
would have alerted Mr Neu as to what was
happening but he chose not to do
anything about
that Mr
Neu his ways are mysterious we will
never be able to understand Mr Niro he
he's too great for for Ordinary People
Like Us so to your question the first
part of what I propose I clearly told
you what I propose but most Indians will
not accept it Indians are very emotional
how can we give up our territory how
dare you suggest we give up our
territory I'm not suggesting we give up
our territory it's already gone are you
capable of taking it back then you take
it back otherwise keep going for now end
the problem in the future we'll see I
know it's our territory I'm not saying
it's Chinese territory China has no
business being in Tibet also from my
perspective but that's a whole different
story so there is that us has no
business in moderating or coming in the
way and thirdly Neu G what can I
say what can I say about
that feminist Slayer okay the question
is
how to be confident all the time and
become mature how to become competent
importance of calm State of Mind how
much important is self-preservation
self-love how to understand the world in
real sense you've asked me like many
questions how to be
confident how to be confident you have
to work towards self-improvement
self-development you should know it
starts with knowing who you really are
who am I most of us don't even know who
we are I have known so much many people
who are afraid to spend time
alone who can't who are scared of being
alone because they are afraid of their
own
company right you should enjoy your own
company you should introspect and
understand who you really
are you should not see yourself the way
others see you other through others
perceptions of you or others opinions of
you what who are are you who do you who
are you really you don't understand that
then you to understand your strength and
weaknesses you to understand where you
want to be what you what what Legacy you
want to leave the day you leave then you
to work towards that you acquire certain
skills for that it's it's not easy it's
really hard to do that it's hard work
the easy thing is to just live an
ordinary mediocre life and just plot
along but if you want to be confident
you want to acquire skills that others
don't have you have to become more
valuable than most people that's what
gives you
confidence one of the easiest way ways
to become confident is to earn money
more money than others I mean you know
that that solves most problems in life
money will not buy you happiness but it
will buy you Freedom money is freedom
money is not happiness what you do with
your freedom is can give you happiness
so one of the things you can do is to
earn money how to be mature well that
that takes
time uh that takes time one of the other
ways of getting becoming confident is by
by by by building up your body by making
yourself Stronger by becoming fit really
fit really strong lift heavy ways and
stuff then it makes you strong
automatically confident uh how to become
competent competent you to work on
yourself you to work really hard
importance of calm State of Mind more
than calm you have to be yeah calm is is
a good good term the more important
thing is that you should not allow your
emotions to rule you hello I'm talking
to
you A lot of people are very emotional
overly emotional and they react to
situations emotionally rather than
saying okay I'm feeling this emotion
great now let me keep that emotion aside
and let me think
calmly and rationally about what's
happening that's a very important skill
to have it's a very important trait to
have so that is what gives you your calm
state of mind that you can be calm Under
Pressure you can do that if you don't
allow your emotions to rule you and that
is something you have to it's a
capability it's an ability to build up
over time everybody has emotions even
the seemingly most stoic person has
emotions just the same as everyone else
but some people are able to master their
emotions how important is
self-preservation I mean it's the most
important thing in the world
self-preservation and and loving
yourself very important you have to do
that how to understand the world in the
real sense by being curious and learning
all the time you know some people I
would say most people stop learning by
the time they are around 40 and then
they will never change their mind stop
learning it's terrible learn learn learn
Roger Penrose is in his 90s he's still
learning something new every day the
people who approach Life as a student
rather than I'm an expert I know
everything they will understand the
world better over time than everybody
else everybody will else will have a
certain dogmatic world viiew that this
is how the world is and that's it nobody
can change my mind such people will
never succeed in life so it's it's I
could do a two-hour session on these
questions only but in brief that's what
I can
say right okay um I saw some interesting
questions okay Mohan Singh asks a good
question great question what are what
are my views on the Indian Air Force in
the Navy indan Navy scrapping their deal
with Uber my goodness I cannot believe
that somebody up there in the leadership
of the if and the Navy actually agreed
to do this deal with Uber
it it is extraordinarily concerning that
that's the kind of leadership we have in
the if in the Indian Navy and when this
matter came out and certain certain
people spoke about it in a podcast the
retired Army and Navy and whatever
military personnel they attacked those
the people who were in the podcast for
using unparliamentary
language what is more important the fact
that you have messed up royalty or the
fact that somebody used certain language
against
you they were trying to deflect the
attention and deflect the blame and
blame the people who use certain
language you cannot use such language
about the Armed Forces what the hell are
you talking about this is an extremely
dangerous
thing giving you know this
deal with Uber it would have allowed
Uber which is an American company to pin
point the locations in real time of
every officer of the if and navy who
would be who who would be uh a member of
this
thing eligible for this it's it's always
going to be the top brass you know the
high ranking
officers and officers not the
non-officer CER of the of the military
so they would be able to pinpoint the
exact location in real time of every
single officer where he goes where he
doesn't go what time time he's where
what is the routine what is the daily
path of each
person where does this person go within
the certain building within this air Air
Force installation or this Naval
installation exactly they can trace out
routes on the map you you imagine the
kind of metadata and intelligence they
can foreign governments can collect from
this it's incredible that somebody in
the leadership high
up agreed to this
I don't know
what what word or term to use for the
level of
stupidity this
entails at the best I can say this is
complete and utter
incompetence that's the best I can say I
can say much worse but I will not say
that
here and I'm not saying that I'll use
unparliamentary language
no I can say much worse without the need
for unparliamentary language my God what
is going
on I hope those officers are are
investigated whoever agreed to these
deals they need to be investigated very
thoroughly it's it's extremely
concerning that we can be so easily
compromised our armed forces can be so
easily
compromised and after all this public
outcry they have decided to start the
process of scrapping the deal so I don't
know how much data Uber may already have
collected it's not just Uber it's other
apps you have a Fitbit watch it it
tracks your entire day exactly where you
are GPS
coordinates every second that can allow
foreign powers to to draw detailed maps
of the comings and goings of various
officers in various installations and
exactly where they go and where and if
you know which officer is is handling
which thing then you know exactly what
that thing is located let's say you have
an
officer hypothetical scenario let's say
you have a number of
officers in the Indian Air Force let's
say hypothetically who are in charge of
Maintenance of nuclear warheads that are
M to various missiles let's say and
somehow the foreign government knows
this that these are the officers now all
you have to do is to track the movements
of those officers to know where they are
going on a daily basis that kind of
gives you the locations of Indian
nuclear war doesn't
it does India's military leadership not
understand
this I
think I think a high school student can
understand this so that how why did they
take this decision that's the question
that's why I'm saying that these
officers at the highest level whoever
signed off on this they need to be
investigated very seriously that's what
I would say this is this is not a joke
this is super serious and the fact that
some Military Officers a bunch of them
on social media are are saying that you
should not have used parli whatever
language I mean they're trying to
deflect attention from where the real
problem lies and that makes me wonder
what their their agendas are really very
serious matter incredible security laps
incredible security
laps in other countries such people
would be court marshaled or Worse o
oh my god
seriously okay let's see this uh shivank
P says H is looking to buy Indian
weapons Paka do you think that India can
start selling more indigenous weapons in
the future especially the Hypersonic
missile we're developing we certainly
should uh aim to become a major arms
exporter I'm not saying we should become
war mongers and start forting wars
everywhere but various Nation lots of
Nations need uh military equipment for
their regular use right every military
wants to be equipped with the best it
can afford so we should have the
objective of becoming one of the major
arms
exporters and we are in the process of
developing a lot of really good Weapons
Systems uh Paka is a great example the
Paka rocket system um Armenia already
has this so if France wants it great
let's let's sell it to them if they if
they are interested we have also sold a
certain missile
to Vietnam is it Philippines Philippines
yes the Philippines is kind of in our
good books so we have S sold a Cutting
Edge the brahos missile to the
Philippines and of course you don't sell
the brahmos to a nation without the
explicit approval from the Kremlin which
is Mr Putin yes
and the Philippines why do they need
brahmos because they're scared of whom
China so Mr Putin sold a weapon system
that could potentially be used against
the Chinese Navy interesting situation
so my point is we should certainly sell
Weapons Systems of various kinds to uh
friendly
Nations um and I'm not sure which
Hypersonic missile we may be developing
but yeah if it's a nation we can trust
then we can explore the possibility of
selling such a weapons system to such
countries so yeah I
agree uh Karan nwat says have you
watched the Dragon Ball series I haven't
I regret these days I have no time to
watch anything I'm lucky if I can get a
one hour spare in a day um so I've heard
of this Dragon Ball thing Dragon Ball Z
and whatnot but I haven't watched it
unfortunately I'm sure it's pretty
good
um okay
tanai says what about the recent
statement made by nagaland regarding the
armed Rebellion against the government
of India and asking for a separate flag
and
Constitution oh yes well you see every
every
every everything is been activated is
being activated in the Far East of India
the northeast of India the major power
in India's Far East the so-called
Northeast is the
church Mr nehu laid the groundwork for
all this by allowing by giving exclusive
access to American missionaries to the
Northeast and allowing them to
completely christianize most of the
Northeast the entire indigenous culture
has been wiped out in States like
nagaland almost all of it okay and what
this has done is that it has made the
church the most powerful entity in these
reg in this
region the church controls the
politicians the church and who controls
the church is the question well there
you have the Deep
State uh so if such statements are being
made I assure you there are far away
powers that are behind
this so uh they're going to activate the
whole of the Northeast and and and turn
it they're objective is to turn the
whole Northeast into a gigantic
nightmare for India Manipur we
understand what's happening we've been
seeing what's happening initially there
were lots of Indians who are feeling
Sympathy For The Cookie terrorists now I
think most people understand what's
really happening right cookie land for
Christ project K that the of the
Americans uh Burma Civil War is also the
the same hand is there over there the
Bangladesh uh coup regime change that's
also the US and uh we know now we now
know what the kind of statements the the
chief minister the current chief
minister of mizoram made on American
soil against India that he views India
as a as an enation right we know
that and we know that a significant
amount of the illegal cookie
infiltration that's happened into into
Manipur has allegedly happened through
mizoram so mizoram is activated Manipur
is the victim state right now they are
victimizing Manipur no end what is the
what is the major sin of the indigenous
people of Manipur the M that they're
Hindus that's their major that's why
Manipur is the target so mizoram is
activated Manipur is the Target now they
may activate other parts of the Far East
of India maybe they will try and
activate nagaland you see in the 20th
century the various Indian governments
had such a horrible step-motherly
attitude toward towards the Northeast
that every single
state every there were there were
multiple insurgencies in every state
every state there had an
Insurgency multiple Insurgent Insurgent
outfits and then other countries took
advantage of that the Chinese started um
started uh aiding and abetting various
Insurgent
outfits uh the East pakistanis were
doing the same thing then the Americans
got involved a whole bunch a complete
mess the government of
India made of the Northeast in the 20th
century and a lot of that what we are
seeing in the Northeast today is the the
Legacy the consequence the natural
consequence of what happened in the 20th
century Manipur has seen over 50 years
of hell no one knows about this so um
yeah the the let's call it the Deep
state they're gonna try and activate
every possible actor in the Northeast
and try and make the northeast of
nightmare for India so India is going to
have its hands full the government of
India is going to have its hand hands
full so let's see how it goes I'm pretty
sure that we will pre Prevail but it's
not going to be an easy ride for
us
okay what else do we have
um feminist Slayer says book
recommendation for learning power
politics look you learn about power
politics by learn by studying hist
history there's no geopolitics book
there's no book about power there's a
book by uh what okay let's go to Google
and I'll try and search for
it um um um um I'm give me a second give
me a second let me go to
Google
and how they rule the
world rule rule the world not PDF I I
don't know PDF download so it's how they
rulle the
world okay it's it's a book by Pedro BOS
think that's an interesting book that's
an interesting book
recommendation if you and then yeah I'm
sure the 48 rules of whatever rules of
power okay this could be an interesting
book if you want to understand the
nature of power in politics and all that
and I'm sure there are more books but I
can't think of others right now so I'll
will stop at that and my friend Vishal
motra says our episode has got an
amazing response I'm glad to hear that
Vish U uh my podcast with Vishal the
second one has come out recently
yesterday I think on his channel so I
would recommend my viewers please go and
watch that as well I think it's about
jinna Gandhi Etc interesting topics so
thank you to Vishal for having me on
your podcast and appreciate your
comment um all right
what other questions can we get into
there's always a lot of questions as
always I hope I get and really
interesting
ones
um okay this one is interesting Manar
says what do you think about yam's
decipherment of the harapan so-called
harapan script or Indus Valley script or
Saraswati synu
script interesting question so yaj we
don't know his real name but he goes as
yam on Twitter on the internet and he
has deciphered the script okay so what's
the this script once again let me put go
to Google and and put that on the
screen so haran
script
har yeah there we have it so the IND the
script or whatever you want to call it
it's this script which has never been
deciphered until now a number of people
have claimed to have deciphered it but
their decipherments were all nonsense
people like maatan mahad Etc completely
fake spirous you know decipherments that
nobody has taken seriously East West
anywhere so now yam says that he has
deciphered the harapan script so let's
go and see
that here we go her script
scpt
and this is the research
paper cryptanalytic decipherment of the
indos script and you you can see the
full PDF it's available for download if
you want to it's it's a pretty long
document roughly 100
pages and he speaks about deciphering
the IND descript as as a
cryptogram okay so whenever this tweet
loads here we have so he's he's tweeted
about that so that's the thing now his
background y's background is that of
computer science and cryptography so he
is
uniquely
positioned to tackle this problem
I have said this a few years ago that we
should use AI we should use cryptography
to to try and decipher the Indus sarasti
script and now he has gone ahead and
done the decipherment and the paper is
available for public
scrutiny so so what excuse me so what do
I think about this so I still haven't
gone through the paper in detail so I
don't know what to say about it
but most likely I'm going to have him on
my podcast we're going to sit face to
face
and we will discuss this at length at
length and hopefully one gets to the
bottom of that during that discussion
it's going to happen in a couple of
months when he will be visiting India
okay so I'm going to discuss this with
him face to face and that episode will
be put out on this channel so and and
before that happens I will make sure
that I read the paper in detail and
understand what it has to say and then
we will revisit this
question
um davic says what do you think about
the government of Canada blaming the
website or whatever it is the the media
Outlet Australia today because they
carried an interview of Dr J
Shanker
hypocrisy what a joke Canada is what the
what a joke the government of Canada is
on the one hand they claim to be all
about freedom of speech and democracy
and blah blah
blah and on the other hand they're
banning media Outlets absolute hypocrisy
these people should be ashamed of
themselves the Trudeau regime should be
ashamed of itself everybody who's a
member of the regime they have the
unrepentant granddaughter of of a former
Nazi who is a very senior minister in
trudo trud trudo's regime and so on so I
think it it completely exposes the utter
hypoc y of Justin tudo and his regime
this is an authoritarian iron fisted
regime masquerading as as as as
something that's what liberal they are
the
exact exact opposite of
liberal so that that's what I can say
about this shameful absolutely shameful
and Shameless people they have no
shame
okay Vin Kumar says the US can't get rid
of that 36 trillion US 1 trillion
interest every the debt can the US get
out of this mess without
dollarization look the US can print
money and repay any any nation's debt so
it's no big deal for the US it's a
system they have created and they are
leveraging the system utilizing it to
the greatest possible extent to their
own benefit to the to everybody else's
detriment the US dollar is nothing but a
piece of paper it is no longer pegged to
the price of gold or anything else it's
it's a freely floating piece of paper
the only thing that gives it give gives
it value is the military might of the US
and the enforced and they enforce it it
as the reserve currency through their
Global power projection
capabilities so as long as there is
there the US is fine they can have as
much debt as you want and if a nation
like China or whoever says pay us back
we are selling your we want our we want
to be repaid the Americans will just
print a whole bunch of money and repay
the Chinese what then what it's no big
deal
so there we have
it bries says do you think the US B2
stealth bummer is reverse engineered
alien technology because I watched Bob
lasar Joe Rogan podcast in which he said
that he worked in Area 51 are there any
secret bases in
India
look ask yourself this
question the testimony of of of Bob
laser on Joe Rogan's
podcast can
it is it valid in a court of
law if
you go to court and for whatever reason
in whichever case you put up this
statement of Bob Lazar on Joe Rogan's
podcast as evidence will the court
accept that as valid evidence no they
will throw it out they will laugh it out
because that's what is called hear say
in Hindi we
say one guy comes and makes these
claims what's the evidence to back up
his
claim did he provide any actual evidence
that he worked there and maybe let's say
he worked there but then just because he
worked there doesn't mean that there is
alien technology there because he claims
that
right so the problem we face with these
claims is that there is no evidence that
backs it up that backs up these claims
no hard
evidence no credible evidence that ever
backs it up unless you want to choose to
believe but then it's just like this
religion or that religion or whichever
religion you believe or you don't
believe belief see science doesn't work
on
belief science is all about questioning
and being skeptical and that's what I'm
being right now I have I have never seen
until today any credible evidence of
alien activity on the planet I've seen
these videos and photos of these weird
UFOs unidentified flying objects now
nowaday they're called uaps unidentified
aial phenomena whatever you want to call
it I've seen those grainy hazy images
and videos of
whatever but that is not credible
evidence anybody can do that with after
effects or whatever even I put up a joke
of a of an image on in on would you like
to see it I've shown it once I'll show
it
again where is my Instagram account let
me open it here and let me put it up
it's like a couple of years ago or at
least a year ago I put it up and uh
let's let's go to my
profile uh give me a second I'm just
trying to open
that uh let's let me put that on the
screen
oops so I'll show you my my my own UFO
image okay let's let's try and find it
it's it's quite a while ago so I'm going
to have to scroll scroll way
down so where is it where is it where is
it let's give it a second I'm going to
unearth it pretty
[Music]
soon I'm going to unearth it pretty soon
where is it that image of UFOs that I
took what looks like UFOs give me a
second
the lot to scroll down
for soon oh here we are
so here's what I wrote over here OMG
look at what my look what my camera
captured north of pangong Lake ladak
India and there's this picture of a UFO
so if I put this up in court will the
court accept it as credible evidence of
UFO activity I hope they
won't I hope they want because it is not
credible evidence it's just a claim made
by somebody and that's what most UFO
images look like so my point is my
answer to your question is that I don't
think the be B2 stealth bomber is
reverse engineered alien technology I
think that many of those UFOs that you
see may be actually secret locked Martin
or Boeing or whatever technology I don't
think they are alien
aircraft and when it comes to secret
alien bases in India I have no idea
whatsoever
unfortunately yeah so there we have
it Rohit says why do you think Russia is
more powerful than China as China has
more powerful economy and a good
army good question good question this is
a fundamental question going to first
principles what is it that makes hard
power how do you calculate hard power
you calculate hard power by using
mathematical formula and what go goes
into these formulas mathematical
formulas your GDP okay that's one thing
that goes into it the other thing that
goes there's a number of things that
goes into it power projection ability
that that's that's a factor you have to
quantify it and give it a number and
then input into the formula GDP I said
your military power how do you calculate
military power the simplest proxy for
calculating military power which is a
very reliable proxy is your annual
military budget your latest military
budget for your nation
then a very very important component a
game changer of a component is your
nuclear
strength now what's Russia's nuclear
strength versus what's China's nuclear
strength China may have what 400 500
Warheads whatever is the publicly
available data we look at that so shall
we look
at nuclear
warheads um um um let's go to Google
then let's see
nuclear
warheads by country
2024 so Russia has 5,000 whatever us
5,000 something China 410 France 290 do
you see the gigantic disparity between
China and
Russia that's a huge Factor then the
fact that Russia has this enormous
territory and it's a complete otari it
is self-sufficient in everything it
doesn't need to import any raw materials
minerals petroleum fertilizer food
products anything from anywhere China is
not in the situation so you factor all
of these various things together and you
construct a hard power score for each
country and then you see that Russia is
like four times more powerful than China
and China is about four times more
powerful than India and the US is
roughly twice as powerful as Russia
which tells you that Russia is the
nation that the US really fears Russia
is a near superpower China is merely an
economic power military they can't they
can't even think of going 2 to2 against
Russia they'll be annihilated if they do
and even Russia's conventional military
strength is
immense certain American Publications
very recently last month itself put
Russia as the most powerful nation in
the world ahead of the US so overall my
point is uh if I say if I say that
Russia is more powerful than China there
must be something behind it I must have
actually done some calculations it's not
just some some some opinion I pulled out
of thin air
right
okay adii says do you think Tulsi gabard
will be the Secretary of Defense look
she she is is an actually is an actual
military person she has served tools of
Duty in Iraq and whatnot so that makes
her a good candidate for being in a role
similar to what you are
saying uh I am pretty sure she will end
up getting some kind of reasonably
senior position in the Trump
cabinet uh what position she gets I'm
not sure if she's a pretty young lady
isn't she early 40s or mid
40s which is okay youth is not a problem
it's not a disadvantage Obama became
president of the age of what 44 or
something probably was younger than Tuli
when he became president so that's okay
um the question is how much does Trump
trust Tuli gabard she used to be a
Democrat and she recently became a
republican but she has shown Republican
Tendencies for quite a while she has
been extremely patriotic she's served
the nation so she has a good track
record good
background um she's a Hindu but that is
okay could that be a factor which could
go against her who knows I don't know uh
only Trump knows so uh I would say that
I pretty certain she will get a
reasonably senior position somewhere in
the Trump cabinet if it is Secretary of
Defense it'll be very interesting but
I'm not 100% sure about that but I'm
pretty sure she will get a reasonably
senior position somewhere in the Trump
Administration I'll be surprised if she
doesn't get a senior position somewhere
in the
cabinet
right okay let's take maybe a couple
more
questions um
AB KRA says could you shed some light on
Germany's focus on India document the
first thing you will see is the cover of
the
document which features prominently a
truncated map of India which excludes
Jammu Kashmir and ladak that's the kind
of focus these Germans want to have on
India this so the very cover of the
document is an attempted slap on India's
face
H and then they say that they want to
focus on India and have more Indian
investment and they want Indian workers
to come to Germany and they want more
Indian students and all that first of
all Germany needs to solve its racism
problem they're extremely racist towards
non-white
people which is weird because there have
so many Turks and whatnot in Germany but
especially when it comes
to people who don't belong to certain
privileged religions there is a lot of
racism Europe overall has has this
racism problem people who travel to
Europe will know about this the
treatment you will get at airports and
all that and so on a lot of
stuff um Germany also has this racism
problem in its Academia a couple a few
years few years back there was this
German Professor lady Professor who said
that she would not accept any Indian
students in her research in in her
Department because Indians have a rape
problem or
something that's the kind of statement
she made and no action was taken taken
against her so I would uh advise Germany
to first
introspect uh solve address its racism
problem and then talk and and then
correct their attitude towards India's
territorial Integrity then maybe we can
talk about their so-called focus on
India see Germany is an inconsequential
Nation that's the fact of the
matter it is a non-sovereign nation
Germany has been under permanent US
military occupation just like Japan
since 1945 the German Constitution was
essentially written by proxy by the
Americans and Germany is now being
de-industrialized and Germany has is
being forced to
swallow I don't know how many countless
immigrants of certain categories Germany
has all kinds of problems I don't see
why India should focus in Germany too
much first of all it's not a Sovereign
Nation and and their economy is not
doing well so yeah they may want Indian
workers and all that or Indian students
I don't think Germany is an attractive
destination for Indian students if
Indian students do want to go abroad I
think they should focus on Nations where
there isn't this attitude of racism
towards them so if you really want to go
out of the country for your studies go
to the US go to the UK or wherever
Canada I would please don't go to Canada
Canada is probably even worse than
Germany so there's lots of options for
Indian students why go to Germany why go
to such a racist Nation why go to nation
that treats its guests and visitors so
poorly okay Surya that says I slightly
feel that you are trying to push some
American agenda into the Indian
Society I do respect you and I'm a huge
fan of work of your work but I don't
trust
you you have an American
agenda and then a question about 48 Laws
of Power excuse me what American
agenda if you could specify the agenda
then I could take this question this
this comment seriously you're just
making a blanket vague statement
accusing me of having an American agenda
or whatever I mean if you want to claim
that I have an agenda of some kind you
should uh maybe substant iate that in
some way giving some specific example of
of some way of some
kind uh
so I'm not sure what what you're trying
to do but huh
okay uh what
else um Grim so bad says Trump's I heard
Trump's planning to buy Greenland what
are My Views I think India is crude in
the the long term the Americans are
overpowered and still haven't peaked I
think the Americans have still still
haven't peaked the Americans are
currently at the peak of their power
historically they have never been this
powerful and they're going to get more
powerful okay America is nowhere
declining it's society's moral structure
may be declining the society may be in
Decline but the military and overall
hard power has never been this high so
America is at the peak of its
strength now is Trump planning to buy
Greenland I think the US America's 250th
anniversary is coming up soon in a
couple of years so maybe they could give
themselves a gift by buying Greenland
who owns Greenland I think Denmark owns
Greenland if the Americans insist I'm
sure the the people of the government of
den Denmark will will oblige and sell
Greenland to America if they want and to
buy Greenland all you have to do is
print a bunch of dollars and give it to
Denmark so I'm sure they can do it if
they want to I'm not sure it's it's
something that's happening it's being
taken up seriously
but if they want
to I'm sure they
can
okay
um can you explain the difference
between power and strength from a
geopolitical perspective there's no
difference between power and strength
from a physics pers perspective yeah
there's a different definition in all
that but from a geopolitical perspective
there's absolutely no difference between
power and strength the two the two terms
the two words are can be used
interchangeably okay Shankar Naran says
is colonizing Mars ethical and what do
you envision for the human race when it
comes to being
multiplanetary why do you
conquer you conquer because you can not
because it's ethical or not
ethics doesn't figure in geopolitical
calculations and consider ations there
is no role for ethics and Morality In
geopolitics we are the nation of
vishnugupta chanakya I think we should
understand
this there is no role for ethics or
Morality In
geopolitics if a nation has the
capability the capacity the ability to
Colon's Mars they will do
it there's nothing right or wrong about
it of of course it's an alien planet
it's not our planet we we belong to
Earth but so what if they can they will
do it and it's going to
happen next 5 years you'll probably have
humans on on
Mars and in the next 20 years you may
have a significant population on Mars
maybe few thousands it's possible it's
going to happen and essentially America
America will own Mars sooner rather than
later there's nothing ethical or
unethical about it they can so they'll
do
it uh now the the question is what do
you envision for the human race when it
becomes when it comes to becoming
multiplanetary Space X has the has
developed the ability to
make Humanity
multiplanetary their latest the the the
most powerful rocket Starship right it's
capable of sending a large number of
people on to Mars on one launch on one
launch vehicle and they plan to launch
multiple vehicles at a
go so yeah in the next few years I think
in the next two years they're going to
launch a number of
unmanned Starships to Mars and if that
works fine in the next two years from
there from there they're going to send
humans to Mars so we are going to be
multiplanetary but it's going to be
Americans mainly who going to be on on
Mars and Elon Musk is and the US
government will decide who gets to go to
Mars and and not and I'm sure I'm pretty
sure that Elon musk's end game is to
become king of Mars let's
see okay we are way past two hours so I
think we're going to end this
session right here so yeah I'm going to
end this here it's it's been a great
series of questions thank you so much
for all the questions apologies to those
of you whose questions I could not take
and we'll have the
same show ask show next week and I'm
going to take a lot more of your
questions then so until then thank you
very much for the questions thank you
for your viewership please keep raising
your standards please keep asking your
questions and I'll see you in the next
episode thank you bye